Guide to the University of Chicago, Yerkes Observatory, Office of the Director Records 1891-1946
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Yerkes Observatory. Office of the Director. Records
1891-1946
118 linear feet (236 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Yerkes Observatory, located in Williams Bay, Wisconsin, is a facility of the University of Chicago's Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics. Known as the home of the last of the great refracting telescopes, the observatory housed the university's Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics until the 1960s, and was the site of some of the most significant research in modern astronomy and astrophysics. This collection contains records of the Office of the Director of Yerkes Observatory, documenting the administrative history of the observatory from before its founding through the mid-1940s.
Information on Use
Access
Open for research. No restrictions.
Historical Note
Yerkes Observatory, located in Williams Bay, Wisconsin, is a facility of the University of Chicago's Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics. The observatory opened in 1897 as the joint creation of three founders: William Rainey Harper, the first president of the University of Chicago; Professor George E. Hale, the observatory’s first director; and Charles T. Yerkes, a wealthy Chicago businessman who provided funds for the erection of the observatory building. On the shores of Lake Geneva, this observatory was designed by Henry Ives Cobb, with landscape architecture by John Olmsted.
Yerkes became known in the astronomical community as the home of the last of the great refracting telescopes, a 40-inch instrument first exhibited at the World’s Columbian Exposition in 1893. The observatory housed the university's Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics until the 1960s, and was the site of some of the most significant research in modern astronomy and astrophysics.
In 1932, the University of Chicago struck an agreement with the University of Texas to construct an observatory endowed by the Texas banker William Johnson McDonald (1844–1926). Texas at that time had neither the funds nor the faculty for its operation. Under the agreement, the observatory was to be constructed and operated under the direction of Otto Struve, with the understanding that eventually University of Texas would assume complete responsibility for McDonald Observatory. As such, Dr. Struve became the first director of McDonald Observatory. The agreement between University of Chicago and the University of Texas was modified in 1959 as Texas’ program in astronomy broadened, and in 1962-1963 the entire operation of McDonald Observatory was placed under the Department of Astronomy at The University of Texas.
Scope Note
This collection contains records of the Office of the Director of Yerkes Observatory, documenting the administrative history of the observatory and the Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics from 1891-1946; the collection also contains editorial and administrative records of Astrophysical Journal.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence of the director from 1891-1946, during which time the position was held by George E. Hale, Edwin B. Frost, and Otto Struve. Typical correspondents included faculty, staff and students at Yerkes Observatory; university administrators; and scientists and organizations outside the university.
Series I contains correspondence from 1891-1903. The correspondence is arranged chronologically in increments of several months, then alphabetically by correspondent or subject.
Series II contains records from 1903-1946. This series consists primarily of correspondence, but also includes material such as financial records, publications and reports. This series is arranged chronologically by year, then alphabetically by correspondent or subject. However, correspondence about routine administrative matters is often filed in subheadings under "University of Chicago" at the end of each year's records.
In Series I and Series II, inventories for the years 1891-1931 contain some lists of individuals or subjects found in each folder; these entries represent "notables," and not a complete list of the contents of each folder. The inventory of Series II includes enhanced descriptive detail for records from the years 1932-1946, when Otto Struve served as Director.
Series III, McDonald Observatory, contains Otto Struve’s correspondence dealing with the planning, construction, opening and early operation of McDonald Observatory in Texas. This collection is organized alphabetically by correspondent or subject, such as “Hale, George E.”, or “Contracts.” The majority of this collection consists of correspondence, but notes, blueprints, contracts, drafts, minutes and newspaper clippings can also be found here. Smaller files of material related to McDonald Observatory are found in Series II.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/phyast.html
Subject Headings
Frost, Edwin Brant, 1866-1935; Hale, George Ellery, 1868-1938; Struve, Otto, 1897-1963; University of Chicago. Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics; University of Chicago. Yerkes Observatory; Astrophysical Journal; Astronomical observatories; Astronomy; Astrophysics; Telescopes; Lake Geneva, Wisconsin; Williams Bay, Wisconsin; Astronomers; Astrophysicists
INVENTORY
- Series I: 1891-1903
  - A-Z, January 1, 1891-October 15, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - A-L, September 26, 1891-April 18, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - M-Z, September 26, 1891-April 18, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - A-Z, April 18, 1892-October 29, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 4-9)
  - A-Z, October 29, 1892-undated, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
  - A-B, September 10, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - C-Z, September 10, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
  - A-B, September 10, 1893-September 15, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - C-Y, September 10, 1893-September 15, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - A-B, September 15, 1894-January 10, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - C-Z, September 15, 1894-January 10, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
  - A-P, January 10, 1895-May 1, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 8-12)
  - R-Z, January 10, 1895-May 1, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - A-Z, May 1, 1895-November 16, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 3-8)
  - A-Z, November 16, 1895-April 1, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - A-K, April 1, 1896-August 1, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - L-Z, April 1, 1896-August 1, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - A-S, August 1, 1896-December 1, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 1-9)
  - T-Z, August 1, 1896-December 1, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - A-Z, December 1, 1896-March 20, 1897 (Box 10, Folder 2-7)
  - A-D, March 20, 1897-July 14, 1897 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - E-Z, March 20, 1897-July 14, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - A-M, July 14, 1897-September 20, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 6-9)
  - N-Z, July 14, 1897-September 20, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - A-Z, September 20, 1897-November 10, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 4-9)
  - A-Z, November 10, 1897-March 3, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - A-L, March 3, 1898-May 25, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 7-10)
  - M-Z, March 3, 1898-May 25, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - A-Z, May 25, 1898-undated, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 4-9)
  - A-Z, September 20, 1898-April 1, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - A-Z, January 1, 1899-May 22, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 6-10)
  - A-Z, May 22, 1899-October 31, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
  - A-F, November 1, 1899-March 31, 1900 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
  - G-Z, November 1, 1899-March 31, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
  - A-D, April 1, 1900-July 6, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - Eclipse, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - E-J, April 1-, 1900-July 6, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - K-Z, April 1, 1900-July 6, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - A-Z, July 7, 1900-November 17, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 4-8)
  - A-Z, November 18, 1900-March 7, 1901 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - A-J, March 8, 1901-June 11, 1901 (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
  - K-Z, March 8, 1901-June 11, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - A-Z, June 11, 1901-October 18, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 4-10)
  - A-Z, October 18, 1901-February 1, 1902 (Box 21, Folder 1-6)
  - A-Z, February 1, 1902-April 9, 1902 (Box 21, Folder 7-11)
  - A-Z, April 9, 1902-June 20, 1902 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
  - A-Z, June 20, 1902-October 16, 1902 (Box 22, Folder 5-10)
  - A-Z, October 16, 1902-January 1, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
- Series II: 1903-1946
  - George Ellery Hale, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - A-B, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Boss, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - B, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - A-Auditor, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - B, 1903, Bausch and Lomb Brashear, J. Burke and James (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - B-C, 1904, Binner and Wells Brashear Computer (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - C, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - C, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - D-F, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 3-5)
  - Gaertner, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Hale, G.E., 1903 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - H, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - H-I, 1903, Harris Heckman (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - J-K, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - L, 1903, Link Belt (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - M, 1903 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - N-O, 1903, Orr & Lockett (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - P, 1903, Pickering, E.C. Press (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Press, 1903 (Box 27, Folder 4-6)
  - P-Q, 1903, Parsons, F.L. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - R, 1903 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - S, 1903 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - S-T, 1903, Snow Telescope Fund Torrey (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - U-W, 1903, Walcott, C.D. Wadsworth Western Electric (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - W, 1903, Warner and Swasey Ward, Montgomery (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Y-Z, 1903 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - A, 1904, Auditor (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - B, 1904, Binner and Wells Brashear (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - C, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - D-F, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - G-H, 1904, Heckman (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - H, 1904, Harris Harper (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Hale, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - I-K, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - L, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - L, 1904, Laboratory Supply Department Link Belt (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - M-N, 1904 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - O-P, 1904, Orr and Lockett Pickering Parsons (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - P, 1904, Payne, W.A. Press Bills (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Press, 1904 (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
  - P, 1904 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - R, 1904 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - S, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - S-V, 1904, Snow Telescope Fund (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - U-W, 1904, University of Chicago Library University of Chicago Power Plant University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent of Grounds (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - X-Z, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - A, 1905 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - B, 1905 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - B-C, 1905, Binner and Wells Brashear Chicago and North Western Railway Company (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - C-D, 1905 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - E-G, 1905 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - G-H, 1905, Gaertner Harper (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - H, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Hale, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - I-J, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - K, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - L, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - M-N, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - O-P, 1905 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - R-S, 1905, Smithsonian Institute (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - S, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - T, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - U-V, 1905, University of Chicago Auditor (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - U, 1905, University of Chicago Business Manager University of Chicago Extension Division University of Chicago Laboratory Supply University of Chicago Library (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago Press, Astrophysical Journal, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - U, 1905, University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent of Grounds University of Chicago Trustees (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - W, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - W-Z, 1905, Weather Bureau (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - A, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - B, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - B, 1906, Binner and Wells Brashear (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - C, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - C-F, 1906, Chicago and North Western Railway Company Agent (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - G, 1906, Gaertner (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - H-J, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - H-J, 1906, Hale Judson (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - K, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - L, 1906 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - M, 1906 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - N-Q, 1906 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - R-Sh, 1906 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Si-Sz, 1906, Smithsonian Institution (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - T-V, 1906 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - U, 1906, University of Chicago Auditor University of Chicago Business Manager University of Chicago Extension Division University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department, bills (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - U, 1906, University of Chicago Library University of Chicago University of Chicago Press (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago Press, Astrophysical Journal, 1906 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - U-W, 1906, Weather Bureau University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Trustees University of Chicago Superintendent Buildings and Grounds (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - X-Z, 1906, Snow Telescope Stenographer correspondence, 1905-1906 Computer correspondence, 1906-1909 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - A, 1907 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - B, 1907 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - B-Ch, 1907, Binner Brashear (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Ci-Cz, 1907 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - C-D, 1907, Carnegie Institution Chicago and North Western Railway Company Agent (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - E-G, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - H, 1907, Hale Hutchinson (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - I-K, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - L, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - M, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - N-O, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - P-Q, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - R-Sh, 1907 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Si-Sz, 1907, Smithsonian Institution (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - T-V, 1907 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - W-Z, 1907 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - U, 1907, University of Chicago Auditor University of Chicago Business Manager University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department, bills (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - U, 1907, University of Chicago Library University of Chicago University of Chicago President’s Office (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1907 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - U, 1907, University of Chicago Press, except Astrophysical Journal University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent Buildings and Grounds (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - A, 1908 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - B, 1908 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - B-Ch, 1908, Brashear Ca-Ch (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Ci-Cz, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - C-D, 1908, Carnegie Institution Chicago and North West Agent (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - E-F, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - G, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - H, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Hale, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - I-K, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - L, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - M, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - N-O, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - P-Q, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - R, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Sa-Sc, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Se-Sz, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - T-U, 1908, University of Chicago Auditor (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - U, 1908, University of Chicago Laboratory Supplies University of Chicago Laboratory Supplies, bill University of Chicago Library University of Chicago (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - U, 1908, University of Chicago President’s Office University of Chicago Press, except Astrophysical Journal (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago Press, Astrophysical Journal. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - U, 1908, University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent Buildings and Grounds (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - U-Wh, 1908 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Wi-Z, 1908 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - A, 1909 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Ba-Bh, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Bi-Bz, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - B-Ch, 1909, Brashear (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Ci-Cz, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - D-E, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - E, 1909, Engraver’s bills previous to 1910 Astrophysical Journal, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - F, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - G, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Ha-Hi, 1909, Hale (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Ho-Hz, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Handlin, W. W., 1909 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - I-J, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - K, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - L, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Ma-Mn, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Mo-Mz, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - N-O, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - P-Q, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - R, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Sa-Sc, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Se-Sn, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - So-Sz, 1909, Smithsonian Institution Stenographer’s correspondence (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - T, 1909 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - U, 1909, University of Chicago Auditor University of Chicago Business Manager (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - U, 1909, University of Chicago Laboratory Supply University of Chicago Library (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - U, 1909, University of Chicago University of Chicago President’s Office (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago Press, except Astrophysical Journal, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago Press, Astrophysical Journal, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago Recorder, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - U-V, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Wa-Wh, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Wi-Z, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - A, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Ba-Bh, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Bi-Bz, 1910, Brashear (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Ca-Ch, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Ci-Cz, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - D, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - E, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - F, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - G, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Halley’s Comet, 1910, Spectral Band Visible May 18, 1910 Earth passing through tail (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Ha-Hi, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Ho-Hz, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - I-J, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - K, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - La-Lh, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Li-Lz, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Ma-Md, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Me-Mn, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Mo-Mz, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - N, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - O, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Pa-Ph, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Pickering, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Pi-Q, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - R, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Sa-Sc, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Se-Sn, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Solar Observatory, (Mount Wilson), 1910 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - So-Sz, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - T, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago Auditor, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Business Manager, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago President’s Office, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago Press, Astrophysical Journal, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago Press, except Astrophysical Journal, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - U, 1910, University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent. Buildings and Grounds (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - U-V, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Wa-Wh, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Wi-Wz, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - W-Z, 1910, Cards of visitors (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - A, 1911 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Ba-Bh, 1911 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Bi-Bz, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Ca-Ch, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Ci-Cz, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - D-E, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - F, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - G, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Ha-Hi, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Ho-K, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - La-Lh, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Li-Lz, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Ma-Md, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Me-Mn, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Mo-N, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Pa-Ph, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Pi-Q, 1911, Pickering (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - R, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Sa-Sc, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Se-Sn, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - So-Sz, 1911, Solar Observatory (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - T, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - U, 1911, University of Chicago Auditor University of Chicago Business Manager (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago Laboratory Supply, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago Library, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - U, 1911, University of Chicago University of Chicago President’s Office (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 7-8)
  - U, 1911, University of Chicago Recorder University of Chicago Superintendent. Buildings and Grounds (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - U-V, 1911 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Wa-Wh, 1911 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Wi-Z, 1911 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - A, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Ba-Bh, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Bi-Bz, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - B-Ch, 1912, Brashear (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Bi-D, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - E, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - F, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - G, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Ha-Hi, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Ho-Hz, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - I-J, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - K, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - L, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - M, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - N-Ph, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Pi-Q, 1912, Pickering (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - R-Sc, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Se-Sz, 1912, Solar Observatory (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - T-U, 1912, University of Chicago Auditor (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - U, 1912, University of Chicago Business Manager University of Chicago Graduate Office (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - U, 1912, University of Chicago Laboratory Supply Department University of Chicago Library (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - U, 1912, University of Chicago University of Chicago President’s Office (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - U, 1912, University of Chicago Press University of Chicago Recorder (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago Superintendent. Buildings and Grounds, 1912 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - U-Wh, 1912 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Wi-Z, 1912 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - A-Bh, 1913 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Bi-Bz, 1913 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - B-C, 1913, Brashear (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - D-E, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - F, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - G, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Ha-Hi, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Ho-J, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - K-L, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - M, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - N-Ph, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Pickering, 1913 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Pi-R, 1913 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Sa-Sn, 1913 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - So-T, 1913 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - U, 1913, University of Chicago Auditor University of Chicago Business Manager (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - U, 1913, University of Chicago Graduate Office University of Chicago Laboratory Supply (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Library, 1913 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - U, 1913, University of Chicago University of Chicago President’s Office University of Chicago Press (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - U, 1913, University of Chicago Purchasing Agent University of Chicago Recorder (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago Grading of Grounds, 1913 (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
  - University of Chicago Superintendent Buildings and Grounds, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - U-V, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - W, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - X-Z, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - A, 1914 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Ba-Bh, 1914 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Bi-Bz, 1914 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Ca-Ch, 1914 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Ci-Cz, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - D-E, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - F, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - G, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Ha-Hn, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Ho-J, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - K-Lh, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Li-Md, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Me-Mn, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Mo-Mz, 1914 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - N-O, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Pa-Ph, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Pickering, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Pi-Q, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - R-Sc, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Se-Sn, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - So-Sz, 1914, Solar Observatory (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - T-U, 1914, University of Chicago Auditor (Box 61, Folder 8)